Finding Aid for Office of the Registrar (University of Michigan) publications, 1926-2013
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Office of the Registrar (University of Michigan) publications 1926-2013
University of Michigan. Office of the Registrar.
353 MB online
8.5 linear feet (in 13 boxes)
0393 Bimu B5 2
Publications produced by the University of Michigan registrar’s office including course descriptions and time schedules, statistics and reports on enrollment, and a variety of brochures, manuals and handbooks.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Publications are received periodically from the unit (Donor no. 100 ).
The record group is open without restriction.
See finding aid for Office of the Registrar (University of Michigan) for historical sketch of the office.
The Publications subgroup of the Office of the Registrar consists primarily of statistical summaries and reports in addition to several brochures, newsletters, and instructional manuals (the latter of which were intended to help faculty and staff understand and provide assistance with the registration process). Categories of statistics include degrees conferred, student retention rates, measures of the student body's diversity, student grades, and enrollment figures by various categories including minority group, graduates by campus, degree level, field of specialization, and credit hours and undergraduate grade point averages. Diversity statistics include a number of reports from the 1970s and 1980s produced by the Office of Affirmative Action with assistance from the Office of the Registrar. Enrollment statistics include the Report of the Registrar of the University and the Term Enrollment and Credit Hour Report. Other significant records include reports on fees and fee regulations.
The Time Schedule, which has been published several different names, documents the courses offered by the University of Michigan each academic year. Print versions of the Time Schedule have also been cataloged under call number 0393 Bimu B5 2. These publications include the Time Schedule (1928-1995), the Schedule of Courses (1995-2002) and the Schedule of Classes (2003-2004). In the Winter Term of 2004, the Office of the Registrar launched a digital-only version of the Schedule of Classes that is available in the Bentley Library digital repository and accessible via links in the online version of this finding aid.
The subgroup also contains technical documentation of the Computer Registration Involving Student Participation (CRISP) system from the 1970s as well as development guidelines and end user documentation of the Academic Record online computerized database from the 1990s.
Subjects:
University of Michigan. Office of the Registrar.; University of Michigan. Office of Registration and Records.; University of Michigan--Schedule of Courses.; University of Michigan--Curricula--Periodicals.
Genre Terms:
Statistics.; Reports.; Manuals.; Brochures.
- Publications
  - Brochures 1957-1984 (Box 1)
  - Calendars
    - Academic Calendar and Registration Schedules 1957-1958 (Box 1)
  - Invitation
    - The Office Mirror, Christmas Party 1939, 1943 (Box 1)
  - Manuals
    - Directions for Advisors 1932 (Box 1)
    - Directions for Registration
      - 1932 (Box 1)
      - 1938/39 (Box 1)
      - 1942/43 (Box 1)
    - Handbook of the Registrar's Office, 1944 (Box 1)
    - Punch Card Processing 1960/61 (Box 1)
    - Registration Information Bulletins
      - 1983 (Box 1)
      - 1987/88 (Box 1)
      - 1988/89 (Box 1)
  - Newsletters
    - Academic Record News, 1993-1994 (Box 1)
    - For the Record: Projects of the Registrar's Office, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Reports and Policies
    - Freshmen Retention Project 1989 (Box 1)
    - Residency Regulations 1988, undated (Box 1)
    - Services of the Office of Registration and Records, 1959 (Box 1)
    - Student Fees and Fee Regulations
      - 1969-1991
      - 1996-1997, .ZIP file
      - 1997-1998, .ZIP file
      - 1999-2000, .ZIP file
      - 2000-2001, .ZIP file
      - 2001-2002, .ZIP file
      - 2002-2003, .ZIP file
      - 2003-2004, .ZIP file
      - 2005-2006, .ZIP file
      - 2006-2007, .ZIP file
      - 2007-2008, .ZIP file
      - 2008-2009, .ZIP file
      - 2009-2010, .ZIP file
      - 2010-2011, .ZIP file
      - 2011-2012, .ZIP file
      - 2012-2013, .ZIP file
      - 2013-2014, .ZIP file
  - Statistics
    - Degrees, Awards, and Graduates
      - Summaries of Degrees and Awards Conferred 1845-2004, 5 folders (Box 1)
      - Graduates by Campus, Field of Specialization, and Degree Level 1988-2001, 5 folders (Box 1)
      - Degree Reports
        (Includes statistics on degrees conferred, broken down by campus, degree level, unit, sex, race, citizenship, and other categories)
        - 2001, .ZIP
        - 2002, .ZIP
        - 2003, .ZIP
        - 2004, .ZIP
        - 2005, .ZIP
        - 2006, .ZIP
        - 2007, .ZIP
        - 2008, .ZIP
        - 2009, .ZIP
        - 2010, .ZIP
        - 2011, .ZIP
        - 2012, .ZIP
    - Diversity of Student Body
      - Affirmative Action Reports (Box 1)
        (Compiled by the Office of Affirmative Action with the Office of the Registrar)
        - 1973/74-1974/75 (Box 1)
        - 1982 (Box 1)
      - Faculty, Students, and Staff of Color: a Statistical Profile
        - 1981/82-1991/92 (Box 1)
      - Minority Students at the University of Michigan 1985/86-1987/88 (Box 1)
      - Enrollment by Unit and Minority Group 1987-2000, 6 folders (Box 2)
      - Minority Reports 1991-1999, 6 folders (Box 2)
        (Includes enrollment statistics)
      - Ethnicity Reports
        - 1999-2001, 3 folders (Box 2)
        - 1999, .ZIP
        - 2000, .ZIP
        - 2001, .ZIP
        - 2002, .ZIP
        - 2003, .ZIP
        - 2004, .ZIP
        - 2005, .ZIP
        - 2006, .ZIP
        - 2007, .ZIP
        - 2008, .ZIP
        - 2009, .ZIP
        - 2010, .ZIP
        - 2011, .ZIP
        - 2012, .ZIP
      - Foreign Student Statistics
        - 1983 (Box 2)
        - 1987 (Box 2)
        - 1990 (Box 2)
        - 1995 (Box 2)
    - Retention of Students
      - Students Returning to the University by Unit of Enrollment 1989-2001 (Box 2)
      - Undergraduate Students Returning to the University 1994 (Box 2)
      - Freshmen Retention Reports
        - 1991, .ZIP
        - 1992, .ZIP
        - 1993, .ZIP
        - 1994, .ZIP
        - 1995, .ZIP
        - 1996, .ZIP
        - 1997, .ZIP
        - 1998, .ZIP
        - 1999, .ZIP
        - 2000, .ZIP
        - 2001, .ZIP
        - 2002, .ZIP
        - 2003, .ZIP
        - 2004, .ZIP
        - 2005, .ZIP
        - 2006, .ZIP
        - 2007, .ZIP
        - 2008, .ZIP
        - 2009, .ZIP
        - 2010, .ZIP
        - 2011, .ZIP
        - 2012, .ZIP
    - Student Enrollment
      (Arranged chronologically)
      - Report of the Registrar of the University 1926-1981, 11 folders (Box 2)
      - Students Admitted by Transfer to the Schools and Colleges of the University of Michigan from other Colleges in Michigan, Fall Semester 1940-1957 (Box 2)
      - Summary of Students 1941-1949 (Box 2)
      - Enrollment Report 1950-1959 (Box 2)
      - Enrollment by Residence, Class Level and Sex 1960 (Box 2)
        (Statistics for 1950, 1953, 1956 and 1959)
      - Enrollment by Class Level, Student Group, Sex and Location, with Rackham Students Distributed According to Field of Specialization
        (Include additional "Credit Enrollment" reports)
        - 1970-1990 (Box 3)
          (Various reports; incomplete coverage of dates)
        - 1972/73-1983/84, 8 folders (Box 3)
        - 1984/85-1987/88, 4 folders (Box 3)
        - 1982-1991 (Box 3)
          (Summary report broken down by "Select Characteristics")
      - Term Enrollment and Credit Hours
        (Various reports, with enrollment statistics by class level, sex, location, type of entry, unit, specialization; includes reports on credit hours)
        - 1988/89-1998/99, 9 folders (Box 3)
        - 1997/98-2001/02, 5 folders (Box 4)
      - Enrollment Reports
        (Various reports, with enrollment statistics by class level, sex, location, type of entry, unit, specialization, citizenship, residency, and age, includes reports on credit hours)
        - 2000, .ZIP
        - 2001, .ZIP
        - 2002, .ZIP
        - 2003, .ZIP
        - 2004, .ZIP
        - 2005, .ZIP
        - 2006, .ZIP
        - 2007, .ZIP
        - 2008, .ZIP
        - 2009, .ZIP
        - 2010, .ZIP
        - 2011, .ZIP
        - 2012, .ZIP
      - First Day of Term Student Counts
        - 2002, .ZIP
        - 2003, .ZIP
        - 2004, .ZIP
        - 2005, .ZIP
        - 2006, .ZIP
        - 2007, .ZIP
        - 2008, .ZIP
        - 2009, .ZIP
        - 2010
          - Fall, .ZIP
          - Winter, .ZIP
        - 2011
          - Fall, .ZIP
          - Winter, .ZIP
        - 2012
          - Fall, .XLXS
          - Winter, .XLXS
    - Grade Reports
      - Grade Distribution
        - 1928/29-1929/30 (Box 4)
        - 1956-1957 (Box 4)
      - Undergraduate Grade Point Averages
        - 1968-1981 (Box 4)
        - 1991-2001, 5 folders (Box 4)
      - Weighted Averages of Grades by Department 1928/29 (Box 4)
  - Summaries of Group Discussions of the Annual Principal-Freshman Conference and Junior College Conference 1950-1952 (Box 4)
  - Technical Documentation
    - Computer Registration Involving Student Participation (CRISP) Bulletins and Publications 1974-1975 (Box 4)
    - U-M Academic Record Project (Online Computerized Database System)
      - General Requirements Documentation 1988 (Box 4)
      - Detail System Design for Previous Experience 1990 (Box 4)
      - Detail System Design Document for Degrees and Certificates 1990 (Box 4)
      - Detail System Design Document for Transfer Credit 1990 (Box 4)
      - Detail System Design Document for Course Tables 1990 (Box 4)
      - Revised Documentation 1995 (Box 4)
  - Time Schedule
    - Time Schedule
      - 1926/27-1961/62 (Box 5)
      - 1962/63-1968/69 (Box 6)
      - 1969/70-1972/73 (Box 7)
      - 1973/74-1978/79 (Box 8)
      - 1979/80-1983/84 (Box 9)
      - 1984/85-1988/89 (Box 10)
      - 1989/90-1993/94 (Box 11)
      - 1994/95 (Box 12)
    - Schedule of Courses
      - 1995/96-1997/1998 (Box 12)
      - Fall 1998 (Box 12)
    - Schedule of Classes
      - Winter 1999 (Box 12)
      - Spring 1999 (Box 12)
      - 1999/2000-2003/04 (Box 13)
      - 2003/04
        - Winter 2004, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2004, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2004, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2004, 1 PDF file
        - Supplement 2003/04, 1 PDF file
      - 2004/05
        - Fall 2004, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2005, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2005, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2005, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2005, 1 PDF file
        - Supplement 2004/05, 1 PDF file
      - 2005/06
        - Fall 2005, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2006, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2006, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2006, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2006, 1 PDF file
        - Supplement 2005/06, 1 PDF file
      - 2006/07
        - Fall 2006, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2007, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2007, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2007, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2007, 1 PDF file
        - Supplement 2006/07, 1 PDF file
      - 2007/08
        - Fall 2007, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2008, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2008, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2008, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2008, 1 PDF file
        - Supplement 2007/08, 1 PDF file
      - 2008/09
        - Fall 2008, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2009, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2009, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2009, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2009, 1 PDF file
        - Supplement 2008/09, 1 PDF file
      - 2009/10
        - Fall 2009, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2010, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2010, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2010, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2010, 1 PDF file
        - Supplement 2009/10, 1 PDF file
      - 2010/11
        - Fall 2010, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2011, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2011, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2011, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2011, 1 PDF file
      - 2011/12
        - Fall 2011, 1 PDF file
        - Winter 2012, 1 PDF file
        - Spring 2012, 1 PDF file
        - Spring-Summer 2012, 1 PDF file
        - Summer 2012, 1 PDF file